Yakumo
八雲…
Sumeragi...
皇…
Did Karen...
卡連
Did he really replace the real Yakumo?
他真的…跟八雲交換身分了嗎
What is going on?
這是…怎麼回事…
SCARLET NEXUS
《緋紅結繫》
♫Felling of tiredness is losing yourself♫
倦怠感 losing yourself
♫How do you still create a relationship each other♫
尚未找到建立關係的方法嗎
♫It’s my awkward friend’s fault♫
有個麻煩的朋友
♫Until death, wanting someone somewhere to embrace me♫
至死都在尋求某人的擁抱
♫While the devil is not here and between the chaos♫
在得以喘息的混沌虛無之間
♫Aiming between win and lose♫
以輸贏之間為目標
♫Not to be running out of patience for now, I’m trying to be careful♫
注意別讓信任走向盡頭 務必小心
♫You’ll see I’m always on your side♫
You'll see I'm always on your side
♫I tried hard to connect today as well♫
今天仍拼命地聯繫著
♫You’re frigid and your roller coaster inside the brain♫
你腦中那冷感的軌道
♫The grungy days and the unprecedented catastrophy♫
搖滾的日子未曾有過的浩劫
♫Where is the glory buried?♫
光榮早已埋葬在某處
♫The lonely monster in a moment♫
這一瞬間寂寞孤獨的野獸
♫The bullet shot by the machinegun goes parallelly♫
與機關槍射出的子彈並列
♫To pierce with the theory♫
射穿所有世間道理
♫I tried hard to connect today as well♫
今天仍拼命地聯繫著
♫The bullet shot by the machinegun goes parallelly♫
與機關槍射出的子彈並列
♫I tried hard to connect today as well♫
今天也仍在一起 清晰地聯繫著
♫You’re frigid and the theory in the brain♫
你那腦中冷感的正義
THE YEARNING IN SLUMBER
(沉睡的思念)
This is different from before.
跟以往…不同…
Brother.
哥哥
He's been here for over 2000 years.
這兩千年來 他都在這
But why?
為什麼
Karen, we need your help.
卡連 有件事希望你協助
In order to destroy the Kunad Gate,
為了消滅岐之門
we need you help.
請你祝我們一臂之力
Back at Arahabaki's secure site,
你在荒吐神時
you used the Red Strings to jump through time
使用了紅色繫線跳躍時空
to 2000 years ago.
而接觸到兩千年前的時代
That created a dimensional entanglement.
因此出現了維度糾纏
As long as the entanglement exists, the Kunad Gate will not disappear.
只要維度糾纏存在 岐之門就不會消失
Yes.
沒錯
At this rate, the whole world will be destroyed.
再這樣下去 世界會毀滅的
We need you to undo it and...
所以 你得解開糾…
It cannot be undone.
解決不了
Only the person who formed the dimensional entanglement can undo it.
讓維度糾纏出現的人 才能解開其糾纏
We did it, so it is possible.
我們都成功了 所以沒問題
I know.
我知道
You know?
你知道…
So why won't you help us?
那為何不幫忙
I cannot undo it. That's the truth.
我解決不了 這就是事實
What do you mean?
什麼意思
Karen, you traveled back in time to save Alice.
卡連 當初你為了救愛麗絲 才跳躍了時空
But why would you go back to 2000 years ago?
但 為何跳躍到兩千年前
I didn't know at first.
剛開始…我也不知道
What do you mean?
剛開始
Yakumo Sumeragi could be a wielder of Red Strings too.
八雲皇 可能是紅色繫線的腦力者
Perhaps I was drawn by his beckoning.
所以 或許我是受到他的牽引吧
You went back to 2000 years ago by accident.
無預警地跳躍到兩千年前
I've been looking everywhere
我拼命地尋找
for a way to save Alice 2000 years from then,
能拯救兩千年後愛麗絲的方法
a way to change the future.
能改變未來的方法
And the answer you've found was to become Yakumo Sumeragi?
你找到的答案 就是成為八雲皇嗎
If I assume the identity of the founding father,
利用建國之父的身分
there must have been something I could do.
應該能做些什麼
So what have you done?
做些什麼 那你做到了什麼
In the future,
在遙遠的未來
there is only one way to save Alice.
唯一能拯救愛麗絲的方法
The only way?
唯一的方法
I must connect myself to Arahabaki.
就是我自己與荒吐神連結
By connecting myself to all the system mainframes,
與所有系統的中樞荒吐神連結
I can alter history.
就能驅動歷史
I can save Alice.
就能拯救愛麗絲
How interesting.
有意思
That can only mean Arahabaki is a bio-computer made from human brains.
所以荒吐神也是 腦部組成的生物電腦囉
Was it you who forcefully
強制入侵我們腦部
invaded our brains?
也是你搞的鬼吧
But whatever the case is,
不過 這是怎麼回事
Alice can't be saved.
實際上 愛麗絲她…她無法復活了
That is why I've tried so hard time and time again.
所以 我才不斷重複
Time and time again?
不斷重複…
The person I was not
不是我的我
jumped through time repeatedly
跳躍時空數次
and became Yakumo Sumeragi.
成為八雲
What are you talking about?
你到底在說什麼
The dimensional entanglement was formed because of it.
維度糾纏也因此產生
The problem cannot be solved even if I undo the entanglement.
就算我解開維度糾纏 也解決不了
Yes, that's it!
沒錯 就是這麼回事
I will create new entanglements!
我會產生新的糾纏
Karen...
卡連
Brother?
哥哥
Karen is two people...
卡連 有兩人
What's going on?
怎麼回事
What are you doing here?
為何 你在這
Why are you here?
你會在這…
That's my question for you!
我才想問
It was you!
你曾說過
You told me becoming Yakumo Sumeragi and connecting with Arahabaki
只要成為八雲 與荒吐神連結
were the only way to save Alice's life.
就有可能是拯救愛麗絲的唯一方法
There was no other way.
除此之外別無他法
Jumping through time, remaining in Arahabaki,
跳躍時空 留在荒吐神裡的…
the trial and error proved that was the only way.
所有嘗試錯誤紀錄證明過了
So why can't I travel 2000 years back in time?
那我為何無法跳躍到兩千年前
What?
什麼
Why did the time jump fail?
為何我跳躍時空失敗了
Explain to me!
解釋清楚
I've given you my aid.
我幫過你了吧
Was it you?
是你嗎…
Tell me everything you know!
快交出所有的情報
I'll take your memories! I'll consume everything!
還有記憶… 我要吞噬一切
He's been absorbed!
吸收了
I see it now.
原來如此
That was what he meant
所謂的與荒吐神連結
by connecting with Arahabaki.
是這麼回事啊
All those memories are mine.
所有的記憶 都是我的…
-What is... -Are you saying...
-什麼 -難道…
Have you acquired new information about Arahabaki.
你得到了荒吐神的情報嗎
What is this?
這是…怎麼回事…
You don't understand anything.
你什麼都不懂
You...
你…
No matter what you do,
不論你做了什麼
Despite hundreds...
都不超過幾百…
Thousands...
幾千…
One of tens of thousands...
幾萬分之一
The me aside from myself...
我以外的我
Do you know
你知道
how many times I've given the same information to my other selves?
我把相同情報給無數的我多少次
Even so, the future can't be changed.
即便如此 仍無法改變未來
Alice can't be saved.
無法救愛麗絲
The only person who has realized it
觀察到這一切的
was me alone.
只有我一人
You are just wasting your time.
你只會白費力氣
You will get nothing out of this.
毫無所獲
You are just one of many in the endless cycle.
無限循環中的其中一人
Give up now.
別再妄想了
Shut it.
閉嘴
I must save Alice!
我一定要救愛麗絲
No matter how many times I try,
不管幾次 我都要救愛麗絲
You two, hand over the Red Strings!
你們兩個 把紅色繫線交出來
Your time jump failed
你之所以跳躍時間失敗
because you couldn't copy Yuito's power.
應該是沒成功複製結人的超腦力吧
Even with your power,
即便是哥哥的超腦力
it's impossible for you to wield the Red Strings for too long.
也很難持續持有紅色繫線
That is why you need to keep copying their power.
所以才要一直複製
Your resistance is futile.
就算你們抵抗也沒用
Me acquiring the Red Strings from you is the inevitable outcome.
我得到紅色繫線是必然的結果
Karen!
卡連
Time jump will destroy the world!
跳躍時空 會毀滅世界的
Does it matter?
那又怎樣
I will travel through time once again
不論要用什麼手段
by any means necessary!
我都要再跳躍一次
Brother...
哥哥
I see.
是嗎
You refuse to help us.
所以你不打算協助我們囉
Hear me out.
聽我說
New Himuka and the Moon have many dirty secrets,
新日向和月球 雖然有許多問題
but destroying the world will not resolve anything.
但世界毀滅的話就什麼都無法解決
We must create a new future for ourselves.
我們必須創造出新的未來
The world built upon history of dirty secrets is worth nothing!
以這樣的歷史織羅而成的世界 一點價值也沒有
I will change the past.
我要改變過去
I will make it happen this time!
這次一定要改變成功
I understand you want to save Alice.
我理解你想救愛麗絲的心情
However...
不過…
Who cares if you understand or not?
我不需要妳的理解
You won't anyway!
妳也不可能理解
His power has been increased.
超腦力增強
Yuito...
結人
Can you do the same?
你們能嗎
Can you just abandon that which is dear to you?
能放棄重要的事物嗎
After going through their harsh and challenging training,
通過許多艱難的訓練
the Scarlet Guardians that will protect the planet has arrived,
拯救這顆星球的紅色守護者
the Scarlet Guardians are none other than the two young men.
兩位年輕的緋紅守護者
Nagi...
那岐…
Private Yuito Sumeragi
結人皇上等兵
versus Private Nagi.
對上 那岐卡門上等兵
Good morning. The weather looks nice today.
早安 今天天氣好像不錯喔
Sister...
姊姊…
It'll be all right.
當然沒問題
After all, it's been your ambition to join the OSF all along.
成為怪伐軍 是你從小的願望嘛
Should we go out and take a look?
要不要出去走走
There is a place I want to check out.
我有想逛的地方
Nagi!
那岐
Yuito,
結人
Hey, Kasane.
重
The truth is...
其實…
You wanted to go back in time...
你曾想過 回到過去…
so you could save me.
救我對吧
If it was you, Kasane...
如果是重
If it was you, Yuito...
如果是結人
you could have saved me.
一定能救我吧
Is the regret eating away at you?
妳很後悔吧
Isn't that right, Kasane?
對吧 重
Back at that moment,
如果 當時那瞬間
had you realized the threat,
妳注意到異狀
I wouldn't have...
我… 我就…
I wouldn't have turned into this!
我就不會變成這副模樣
The regret must be eating away at you.
你很後悔吧
Back at that moment...
如果 當時那瞬間
Where is Nagi?
那岐人呢
I lost contact with him after he was sent to the hospital.
他被帶到醫院後 就沒跟我聯絡了
Had you come looking for me, I would still be alive.
如果你來找我 就不會演變成這樣
I felt so strange.
我…變得莫名其妙
There was a voice that
要我殺你的聲音
wanted me to kill you.
在耳邊響起
I hated fighting, it disgusted me.
我明明不想戰鬥 這麼厭惡
I was so afraid, but I couldn't resist.
我很害怕 卻無法反抗
You are right, I regret it.
我的確 後悔過
Even the slightest difference
只要做出稍微不同的選擇
is enough to create a different future.
未來 或許就會不一樣
However...
可是
It doesn't matter where we are, we can only make one choice.
無論何時 我們只能做出一種選擇
Making choices and moving forward is part of life.
人活著 就得做出選擇往前走
That is the only thing we can do.
只能這麼做
At the moment, we must make the right choice.
只能做出 當下最正確的選擇
In the end,
結果你們兩個
you set aside important matters
為了自已的私慾
over your own selfish desires.
而把重要事物一腳踢開
Your yearning is nothing but a joke.
你們的思念不過就這點程度
No! It was because of Nagi...
不對 正因為有那岐…
Stop talking like you know everything!
別說得一副你很懂似的
It was all because of Nagi!
正因為有那岐
But it's not just Nagi's pain,
不只是那岐 任何人發生什麼不測
we can't turn a blind eye to people's suffering!
我們都不能閉上眼睛否認一切
That's what I've learned.
這就是我的體悟
We can't change the past.
不是改變過去
We must move toward the future.
而是前往未來
We must do it.
我們非這麼做不可
These are just excuses.
這是你們的藉口
Abandoning your past, denying the tragedy that had taken place,
放棄過去 否認已發生的悲劇
you are running away from the problems!
這就是逃避問題
I will not do the same.
我不會逃的
I will save Alice no matter what the cost.
無論如何我都要救愛麗絲
Karen, listen to me.
卡連 聽我說
There must be a future Alice wanted for you to have.
你應該有 愛麗絲期望你 走向未來的記憶
What did you say?
什麼
Try to remember.
快想起來
Alice wouldn't want you to destroy the world just to save her life.
愛麗絲並不希望 毀滅世界來拯救自己
Don't you dare say her name!
你不准提愛麗絲
You should see it by now!
現在的你應該能理解
You are already connected to Arahabaki!
因為你與荒吐神連結了
Remember what Alice wanted.
快想起愛麗絲的思念
Silence!
閉嘴
I will not change my mind!
就算知道什麼 我也不會改變想法
I don't care what it takes!
不管有多麼困難…
I will not change my mind now!
我都不會改變…
I will not...
我不會…
Hand it over!
把你們的
Hand over your Red Strings!
紅色繫線交出來
Kasane, let's go!
重 我們上
After I get the Red Strings from you,
只要得到紅色繫線
both of you will be useless to me.
你們就沒用了
Kasane, do what Karen just did!
重 跟卡連一樣
What?
什麼
Search for the memory inside Arahabaki.
從荒吐神的記憶裡尋找
Search for the real Alice.
尋找愛麗絲真正的身影
She must have been a great person.
她是位很好的人吧
The fact that you miss her so much says everything.
能讓你如此思念她 便是最好的證明
Alice...
愛麗絲
Thank you.
謝謝
What's wrong?
怎麼了
It's Karen.
卡連他…
He's always stuck his neck out for me.
總是幫助我
And just now, he must have
可是今天 因此害他…
suffered some serious injuries because of me.
那絕非一點皮肉傷吧
That's just who he is.
他就是這種人
It's not that I don't want his help,
我不是希望他別再幫我
but I want him to love himself more.
而是希望 他能更加善待自己
That's right.
就是啊
I want to have him by my side.
我想一直跟他在一起
That means I need to become stronger.
所以我得更堅強
But even so, it won't stop him from risking his life for you.
即便如此 他還是會繼續保護妳吧
You are right.
是啊…
It's all the more reasons to work harder.
所以 我得更努力才行
To make sure Karen won't be worried about me again,
為了讓卡連不再為我擔心
I must work harder.
而持續加油努力
After all, I want Karen to be happy.
因為我希望 卡連能得到幸福
Karen Travers.
卡連崔佛斯
How do you feel right now?
現在的你過得如何
Do you feel happy?
覺得幸福嗎
Alice...
愛麗絲…
Is it over now?
結束了嗎
Yes.
是啊
I...
我…
I will never agree with this!
我 不認同
Brother!
哥哥
Yuito!
結人
I've copied your Red Strings.
我已經複製你的紅色繫線了
With this, I can finally make it happen.
這樣我就能…
Karen...
卡連…
You should have seen it.
你應該看到了
You should know what Alice really wanted.
愛麗絲真正的心情
Alice.
愛麗絲
Wait for me, Alice.
愛麗絲妳等著
I will...
我一定會…
I will not give up.
我不會停止的
This time...
這次一定會…
I must save you!
一定能救愛麗絲
Brother, it's enough.
哥哥已經…
Yuito.
結人
This is the only way.
只能這麼做了
Karen!
卡連
♫I'm troubled by my own yearning♫
被追求的憧憬所困
♫Unveil the blocked sun ray♫
揭開被阻擋的搖曳陽炎
♫There's a stranger in me♫
There's a stranger in me
♫That I've never seen♫
從未見過
♫I can not soar in the sky without fear♫
自己能不再恐懼翱翔高空
♫I'm spreading my wings♫
I'm spreading my wings
♫Dancing gracefully like a bird♫
華麗舞步的鳥兒
♫And gazing towards the scarlet sky♫
仰望染紅的天空
♫I chased after the gust♫
追過了強風
♫The scenery spreads into the ever-changing world♫
景色蔓延在千變萬化的世界裡
♫Inside the intertwined brilliance♫
在交錯的光芒中
♫I'm still searching for tomorrow's direction♫
持續尋找明天的行徑方向
♫Tomorrow's in your hands♫
Tomorrow's in your hands
♫Don't tell me now you're afraid♫
Don't tell me now you're afraid
♫There's no time to waste♫
There's no time to waste
♫Go forward♫
前進
♫Have no fear for anything♫
不再畏懼何物
♫Now, let's go♫
走吧
♫Into a brand new day♫
Into a brand new day
OPERATION KUNAD GATE
(消滅岐之門作戰)